The True Master of the Metal Breath
Let me get this straight. You'll help us take down the Star Guardian?
Who the heck are you, anyway?!
My name is Flame Nova. I came here to give you some advice.
Advice?
I already know that you revealed the existence of us, the Metal Cardbots, through the press.
It was a mistake to pick a fight with the Star Guardian.
Even if the two of you attacked together, you'd still be no match for him.
What was that?!
What is that supposed to mean?
The Star Guardian is in possession of the treasure of Deus Machina.
Are you talking about that Metal Breath the boy was wearing?
Yes. I'm talking about the invincible power granted by Deus Machina, the mother computer of Planet Machina.
As long as he has this power, there is no chance for any of you to win.
Let's do this fair and square.
That coward! He'd been hiding that power all along, and yet he wanted to keep it fair and square?!
You think you can easily beat me even when you're not at full strength?!
- Flame Nova. Who exactly are you? Why are you telling us about the treasure of Deus Machina?
- God dang it!! If only my brother didn't interrupt me-
Because I like people like you.
The daredevils who will stand up for themselves no matter how strong their opponents are.
Sky Gallop. Take me to Mowtown.
I have to see the invincible power granted by Deus Machina with my own two eyes.
Now, then...
YOU IDIOT!!!
What's all the commotion?!
Jun! Are you telling me that you went all the way to their hideout... just to come back empty-handed?!
He must’ve thought that fighting fist to fist would bring them closer together.
Violence only breeds more violence, so they say.
Don't you think it was hopeless from the beginning? Just the idea of sharing your heart with the Hidden Cardbots was-
It's not hopeless!!
Sheesh...
Sky Gallop was the one who said that it wasn't fair when Flash Vector interfered.
Not to mention Flash Vector only did that because he didn't want us to take his younger brother away.
Then let me ask you a question, Mr. Jun. What was the whole point of you visiting their hideout?
Uhhh... What was it again?
You went there to seal the Hidden Cardbots!
And to figure out where my dad is from Sky Gallop!
Ah, yeah! Those were the reasons! Haha...
Did you actually forget about that?
I guess that's just how Jun is...
At least now we know where their hideout is!
Oh, yeah! 90 kilometers off the eastern coast of Mowtown... It's at an abandoned oil rig!
Oh, the ocean is like my front yard! Let me sink it, and the problem is solved!
We can't do that!!
I'm not trying to bring them to their knees by force.
I just want to build a world where Metal Cardbots and humans can live together!
I'll be taking my leave now.
Glober?
May your wish come true!
Glober...
Adieu!
Is it okay to just let him go like this?
Whenever I talk to that guy, I find myself caught up in his words.
I think that's because Glober is an inspiration to you.
An inspiration?
Glober is a man like the wind. He is as free as the winds that sweep across the Earth.
Jun, don't you want to live as freely as he does?
Blue Cop, you're a poet!
Oh look, the emotions are overflowing like oil...
What's he talking about?
To be honest, I've been reading a poetry book these days...
Oh! I read that book too!
You're already here, Jun! Perfect timing. We have a favor to ask of ya.
Hello.
Ms. Mona and... Kent? W-what kind of favor?
I'll be upfront about it.
That Metal Breath you're wearing... Can we borrow that for just a day?
Eugh, disgusting...
Are you okay?
Why are you asking him this all of a sudden?
Well, Kent's parents own a flower shop...
and they said that a Metal Cardbot once destroyed their business.
Come on. We can't leave our store unattended for too long.
We have a lot of orders today!
Did they get hurt?!
Fortunately, no one was hurt.
But it's been reported in the papers lately that Metal Cardbots are invaders from outer space.
No! They're friends!
I thought that if only I had the Metal Breath, Mama and Dada would understand...
We can't do much for you...
This is a token of friendship with Metal Cardbots. It can't be handed over or lent to anyone else.
Ah! I have an idea.
What's that?
Woah!
With this, the Metal Cardbots will follow your orders.
Really?
But isn't that just...
...An imitation made out of paper?
Red Blitz!
Transform into a sports car!
Eh?
Hey, don't just stand there.
He's talking about you.
EH?!
Transform! Transform!
The Crimson Flash, Red Blitz! Transform!
Red Blitz! Launch Fist Missiles!
Eh? Hey! I prefer kicking things!!
Yeah, yeah! Name it "Mega Shrimp Kick!"
What did you say?!
Cielo! Transform into a fighter jet!
The-the champion of the sky, Cielo! Transform!
- Now look at you! Hahahaha!
- After this, you're so dead...
Blue Cop, let's go apologize to Kent's parents.
We should explain that Metal Cardbots aren't bad people.
- Musclehyde! Transform!
- Uh, who's that over there? The one standing next to Kent.
There's no one there...
Kent!
So this is the treasure of Deus Machina.
Flash Vector!
How long have you been standing there?!
It's a secret. I enjoy being stealthy.
We had no idea he was there all along!
He used his stealth mode. Blue Cop!
Give Kent back!
Too slow.
I'm not only stealthy, but fast too.
Bet you're not faster than me!
Darn!
Wh-what the heck is this?! I can't move!
Stingers! Those stingers can restrict the movements of Metal Cardbots!
Then we can easily-
Mr. Edd!
Jun, what should we do? If we act without thinking...
Yeah. We'll end up frozen like we did with Buster Gallon.
What an annoying situation.
I knew it would be a simple task, but this was too easy.
The treasure of Deus Machina... Acquisition complete!
Kent!
Everyone, Take Back!
Uncle Edd!
Blue Cop! Let's go after him!
Roger!
I'll go with you!
Cielo! Take Peruru with you!
Got it.
What's all the commotion about?
Mr. Blastrain! My kindergartner is in danger. Can you save him, please?
That would prove difficult for me. I am a sealed bot, so I shouldn't act without orders.
Pretty please!
This is a matter of the future between Metal Cardbots and humans!
Very well, then!
Blastrain, temporary operation activated!
Stop at once and release the boy!
You really are a Star Guardian. Persistent.
Dodge!
Yikes!
Stop playing games!
Farewell, then.
Peruru! Can you see anything?
I can't. He's probably using stealth mode!
I can figure out where he went if I could use my Homing Magnum.
Jun, what should we do?
Ah!
Cielo, Peruru! Chase after Flash Vector by following his shadow!
Shadow?
Ah, great idea!
He can hide himself, but he can't hide his own shadow!
There!
How should we do this? We can't use my weapons 'cause that'll endanger Kent.
Then that leaves only one option!
Peruru!!
What?!
Big sis!!
Kent! Are you oka-
At least tell me before you do something like that!
Peruru!
Gosh, you're Mukara's descendent alri-
Darn it! We let our guard down!
I don't know how an Earthling kid like you got your hands on a shard of Machinasium.
But I'm putting an end to this game of tag!
Mukara's spear feels weaker than before...
Now, give me the treasure of Deus Machina right n- Huh?
Huh? That sounds like...
Ahem! Ah, ah, ah! The next stop is Flash Vector. Flash Vector Station!
Blastrain, arriving on time!
Blastrain! Be careful of those strange stingers he shoots!
Do not worry about that. But for now, please step away from the tracks!
O-okay! Let's move, guys!
It's no use!
Those stingers send a harmful electric current into Metal cardbots, paralyzing us. Does it not?
I once ran on a railroad track that didn't suit me, and I went out of control.
But with Mr. Edd and Mr. Teo's help, I am now able to block out any kind of electromagnetic current.
And that applies to your stingers as well!
Now, I can run on any kind of railroad!
What are you talking about?
Alright! Combine, Blastrain!
Affirmative!
You can't keep up with my speed just because you got bigger!
In that case, how about slowing you down instead?!
Well done! Blastrain, Set Up!
Blastrain! Crossover Storm!
Crossover Storm!
Metal Cardbot! Change Up!
Sparking Hammer!!
Spark Bit?!
I came to save you, bro!
It was unnecessary...
(I believed in you, my little brother!!) (FX-italic)
We apologize for interrupting a duel that befell an end.
Sky Gallop!
'Tis too soon to let Flash Vector go.
Master of the Metal Breath, will thou fight until thou hast locked us all in that bracelet?
I'm not locking you up!
I just want to keep you all safe until the rest of humanity is ready to live alongside you!
And if I have to fight for that... I will!
Thou shall continue thy fight. We shall continue ours.
I look forward to the next duel, to see whom the final victor shall be.
Sky Gallop!
Yes, my lady Peruru?
Where is Gigantrex?
Thou shall soon find out.
I'll be coming for you tomorrow! Be prepared!
That decision is not yours to compose, Spark Bit.
What?! Why??
Please stop talking, Spark Bit...